export const questions = [
  {
    question:
      "What should you do in case your vehicle breaks down on an expressway? Check all that apply.",
    choices: [
      "Open your trunk and hood",
      "Stand on the expressway and flag down passing drivers for help",
      "Call for help using a mobile phone or an expressway phone",
      "Park as far to the right as possible",
      "Put your hazard warning light on",
    ],
    answer: [
      "Open your trunk and hood",
      "Call for help using a mobile phone or an expressway phone",
      "Park as far to the right as possible",
      "Put your hazard warning light on",
    ],
  },
  {
    question: "What will happen when your front tire blows out?",
    choices: [
      "The back end will sway towards the side of the blowout",
      "The back end will sway away from the blowout",
      "The front end will pull towards the side of the blowout",
      "The front end will pull to the opposite side of the blowout",
    ],
    answer: "The front end will pull towards the side of the blowout",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What should you do when an ambulance comes up behind you flashing red lights and/or sounding its siren?",
    choices: [
      "Stop as soon as you can",
      "Maintain your speed, let the ambulance driver will find a way around you",
      "Speed up so that you don't hold the ambulance",
      "Pull over to the right and slow down or even stop if necessary",
    ],
    answer: "Pull over to the right and slow down or even stop if necessary",
  },
  {
    question:
      "While driving the hood of your car lifts up blocking your vision. What should you do? Check all that apply.",
    choices: [
      "Look through the gap underneath the hood or out of the side window",
      "Brake suddenly so you don't leave the road",
      "Pull to the side of the road and refasten the hood",
      "Turn your headlights on and look out of the side window",
    ],
    answer: [
      "Look through the gap underneath the hood or out of the side window",
      "Pull to the side of the road and refasten the hood",
    ],
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case of an accident, the first duty of the driver involved is to:",
    choices: [
      "pick-up the injured person and take him to the nearest hospital",
      "report the accident to the nearest hospital",
      "report the accident to the nearest police station",
    ],
    answer: "report the accident to the nearest police station",
  },
  {
    question: "When a vehicle starts to skid, what should the driver do?",
    choices: [
      "Immediately step on the brakes",
      "Hold firmly on to the wheel while slowing down the vehicle",
      "Turn the wheels to the opposite the direction of the skid",
    ],
    answer: "Hold firmly on to the wheel while slowing down the vehicle",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In case of injuries caused by an accident, the duty of the uninjured driver is to:",
    choices: [
      "call a physician",
      "keep the victim lying down",
      "try to determine who is at fault",
    ],
    answer: "call a physician",
  },
  {
    question: "What will happen when your rear tire blows out?",
    choices: [
      "The back end will sway towards the side of the blowout",
      "The back end will sway away from the blowout",
      "The front end will pull towards the side of the blowout",
      "The front end will pull to the opposite side of the blowout",
    ],
    answer: "The back end will sway towards the side of the blowout",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When a vehicle is stalled or disabled, the driver must park the vehicle on the shoulder of the road and:",
    choices: [
      "switch on the parking light",
      "install the early warning device",
      "switch on the parking light and install the Early Warning Device to the front and rear of the motor vehicle",
    ],
    answer:
      "switch on the parking light and install the Early Warning Device to the front and rear of the motor vehicle",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If you are the first to arrive at the scene of an accident, which of the following should you do:",
    choices: [
      "mind your own business",
      "offer all reasonable assistance",
      "move past the accident scene to avoid traffic build up",
    ],
    answer: "offer all reasonable assistance",
  },
  {
    question:
      "As per RA 4136, the brakes on every vehicle (other than a motorcycle) must:",
    choices: [
      "consist of a good foot and hand brake",
      "consist of a good foot break that works as intended",
      "consist of brake fluid at all times",
    ],
    answer: "consist of a good foot and hand brake",
  },
  {
    question: "What is not a good trait of a driver?",
    choices: [
      "Driving recklessly and under the influence of alcohol",
      "Driving while listening to music",
      "Driving fast on a highway",
    ],
    answer: "Driving recklessly and under the influence of alcohol",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A safe speed to drive your car under adverse conditions depends on:",
    choices: [
      "authorized speed limit",
      "your driving style",
      "the vehicle type",
    ],
    answer: "authorized speed limit",
  },
  {
    question: "Night driving is dangerous because:",
    choices: [
      "street lights tend to blur your vision",
      "more vehicles are on the road at night",
      "the distance we can see ahead is reduced",
    ],
    answer: "the distance we can see ahead is reduced",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What habit will help you prevent getting a fixed-stare and resist distraction?",
    choices: [
      "Looking at the ground",
      "Moving your eyes regularly by looking near and far",
      "Gauging another car's speed",
    ],
    answer: "Moving your eyes regularly by looking near and far",
  },
  {
    question: "Seatbelts must be worn by children aged:",
    choices: ["5 years and above", "7 years and above", "6 years and above"],
    answer: "6 years and above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is the maximum speed limit on expressway for cars?",
    choices: ["60 kph", "80 kph", "100 kph"],
    answer: "100 kph",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Graft and corruption in the traffic enforcement system can be eliminated by:",
    choices: [
      "understanding the road and traffic rules and regulations",
      "understanding the road and traffic rules and regulations",
      "self discipline by drivers and obeying traffic rules and regulations",
    ],
    answer:
      "self discipline by drivers and obeying traffic rules and regulations",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Eating, drinking, reading, or doing anything that may take your attention from driving is:",
    choices: [
      "never allowed",
      "allowed if you have a professional driver's license",
      "allowed as long as you can handle it",
    ],
    answer: "never allowed",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Before a private motor vehicle owner can apply for a DOT franchise, the motor vehicle must be registered with the:",
    choices: [
      "Constabulary Highway Patrol Group",
      "Philippine Motors Association",
      "Land Transportation Office (LTO)",
    ],
    answer: "Land Transportation Office (LTO)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to the Philippine Clean Air Act of 1999 (R.A. No. 8749)",
    choices: [
      "All road users have the right to breathe clean air.",
      "Every citizen must strive for their right to breathe clean air.",
      "Every citizen has the right to breathe clean air.",
    ],
    answer: "Every citizen has the right to breathe clean air.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To avoid suspension or revocation, how many days must a driver with an apprehended license settle his case with LTO?",
    choices: ["within 15 days", "within 10 days", "within 30 days"],
    answer: "within 15 days",
  },
  {
    question: "To have one's driver's license suspended means to:",
    choices: [
      "have it revalidated by the LTO",
      "have it taken away permanently by the LTO",
      "have it taken temporarily by the LTO",
    ],
    answer: "have it taken temporarily by the LTO",
  },
  {
    question: "To obtain one’s driver’s license, one must be at least:",
    choices: ["16 years old", "17 years old", "18 years old"],
    answer: "18 years old",
  },
  {
    question: "A pre-trip inspection should be completed:",
    choices: [
      "before and after operating the motor vehicle",
      "after operating the motor vehicle",
      "before operating the motor vehicle",
    ],
    answer: "before operating the motor vehicle",
  },
  {
    question: "It is not considered safe driving on an expressway when:",
    choices: [
      "driver is driving at 80kph",
      "driver is driving at 60kph",
      "driver keep changing lanes without signaling",
    ],
    answer: "driver keep changing lanes without signaling",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When you do not see the wheels of the vehicles in front of you, should you do?",
    choices: [
      "Slow down and get back to a safer following distance",
      "Turn your fog light on",
      "Increase your speed until it becomes visible",
    ],
    answer: "Slow down and get back to a safer following distance",
  },
  {
    question: "Your speed while driving at night should keep on:",
    choices: [
      "the distance that you can see where you come to a complete stop within the distance that your headlights can light up.",
      "the speed since you have enough lighting anyways",
      "a slow speed to avoid road crash",
    ],
    answer:
      "the distance that you can see where you come to a complete stop within the distance that your headlights can light up.",
  },
  {
    question: "When driving at night, you should:",
    choices: [
      "decrease your speed",
      "drink coffee so you won't fall asleep",
      "always turn your headlights on",
    ],
    answer: "decrease your speed",
  },
  {
    question: "How close should another car be before you dim your headlights?",
    choices: ["150 meter", "100 meter", "200 meters"],
    answer: "150 meter",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If you are backing up in a straight line, turn and look behind and over your shoulder at:",
    choices: ["right", "left and right", "left"],
    answer: "right",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The blind spot is the area to your right or left that you do not see in the side view mirror, what will you do before you back up?",
    choices: [
      "look at the rearview mirror",
      "get out of the vehicle and scout the area behind you first",
      "turn your head to see that the way is clear",
    ],
    answer: "get out of the vehicle and scout the area behind you first",
  },
  {
    question:
      "At an intersection with traffic signals, if you (car A) are not in the proper lane to make a right or left turn you should:",
    choices: [
      "continue ahead and find a u-turn",
      "just continue ahead",
      "continue to make the turn",
    ],
    answer: "continue ahead and find a u-turn",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When approaching a flooded area and you have to go through it, what should you do?",
    choices: [
      "Increase your speed so you get through immediately",
      "Maintain your speed as most have water insulation anyways",
      "Proceed at a very slow speed",
    ],
    answer: "Proceed at a very slow speed",
  },
  {
    question:
      "While driving with maximum speed and you have to stop suddenly, you should:",
    choices: [
      "apply your brakes heavily with steady pressure",
      "apply your foot and hand brakes gently with steady pressure",
      "apply your brakes gently with steady pressure",
    ],
    answer: "apply your brakes gently with steady pressure",
  },
  {
    question: "On a wet road, you must:",
    choices: ["maintain speed", "slow down", "increase speed"],
    answer: "slow down",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When planning to overtake a slower vehicle in front of you at night, you should:",
    choices: [
      "bow your horn so he gets alerted",
      "flick your dimmer, switch two or three times to signify your intention to the driver of the vehicle that you intend to overtake",
      "put hazard lights on so he knows you're about to overtake",
    ],
    answer:
      "flick your dimmer, switch two or three times to signify your intention to the driver of the vehicle that you intend to overtake",
  },
  {
    question:
      "You are preparing to exit an expressway, when should you start reducing speed?",
    choices: [
      "immediately before entering the deceleration lane",
      "immediately upon entering the deceleration lane",
      "immediately upon spotting the deceleration lane",
    ],
    answer: "immediately upon entering the deceleration lane",
  },
  {
    question:
      "While driving with a maximum speed and you have to stop suddenly, you should:",
    choices: [
      "apply your brakes gently with steady pressure",
      "apply your hand brakes gently with steady pressure",
      "apply your brakes abruptly with hard pressure",
    ],
    answer: "apply your brakes gently with steady pressure",
  },
  {
    question: "When driving on mountain roads during daytime, you should:",
    choices: [
      "blow your horn every 15 seconds",
      "blow your horn whenever you sense an oncoming vehicle",
      "blow your horn when approaching a blind curve",
    ],
    answer: "blow your horn when approaching a blind curve",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What light shall be used when vehicles are parked on the highway at night?",
    choices: [
      "Headlight",
      "Parking lights or lower-beam headlights",
      "Signal lights",
    ],
    answer: "Parking lights or lower-beam headlights",
  },
  {
    question: "When loading or unloading passengers, we usually stop at the:",
    choices: [
      "right side of the road nearest the sidewalk",
      "middle of the road",
      "intersection",
    ],
    answer: "right side of the road nearest the sidewalk",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If you are parking uphill without a curb, turn the wheels towards the:",
    choices: [
      "edge of the street",
      "other side of the street",
      "middle of the street",
    ],
    answer: "edge of the street",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A driver ________ park or stop at the side of the road within 6 meters of a crosswalk because it reduces the visibility of pedestrians to other drivers.",
    choices: ["should not", "is capable", "is allowed"],
    answer: "should not",
  },
  {
    question: "Whenever you park, remember to:",
    choices: [
      "shift the gear to neutral",
      "turn off the engine and engage the handbrake",
      "close the windows",
    ],
    answer: "turn off the engine and engage the handbrake",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Never park or stop at the side of the road with a fire hydrant, you may only park with a distance of at least:",
    choices: ["3 meters", "4 meters", "5 meters"],
    answer: "5 meters",
  },
  {
    question: "The vehicle is parked if:",
    choices: [
      "the vehicle is stationary and remains inactive in a place for an appreciable period of time",
      "The vehicle is not moving while loading passengers in",
      "The vehicle is not moving while unloading passengers",
    ],
    answer:
      "the vehicle is stationary and remains inactive in a place for an appreciable period of time",
  },
  {
    question: "When parking downhill, you should turn your front wheels:",
    choices: [
      "toward the curb of the sidewalk",
      "away from the curb",
      "any direction will do",
    ],
    answer: "toward the curb of the sidewalk",
  },
  {
    question: "When you are parked at the side of the road at night, you must:",
    choices: [
      "warn others by turning on your 4 way emergency flashers",
      "be sure to stay awake and ready to move",
      "warn others by turning on your headlights",
    ],
    answer: "warn others by turning on your 4 way emergency flashers",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A driver must not park or stop at the side of the road with a “STOP SIGN” or a traffic control signal because it reduces visibility for other drivers, especially when it is within:",
    choices: ["4 meters", "5 meters", "6 meters"],
    answer: "6 meters",
  },
  {
    question: "Parking lights may be used:",
    choices: [
      "at anytime",
      "for parking and when visibility is poor",
      "when driving on a well-lighted streets",
    ],
    answer: "for parking and when visibility is poor",
  },
  {
    question: "You may never park:",
    choices: [
      "on a crosswalk",
      "on a one-way street",
      "within 5-meters of a fire-hydrant",
    ],
    answer: "on a crosswalk",
  },
  {
    question: "Parking is considered as a violation when a motor vehicle:",
    choices: [
      "parks at the entrance and exit of hospital and fire stations",
      "parks at the entrance and exit of an industrial establishment",
      "parks at the entrance and exit of a residential establishment",
    ],
    answer: "parks at the entrance and exit of hospital and fire stations",
  },
  {
    question: "What is considered as a parking violation?",
    choices: [
      "parking in a one-way street",
      "parking without hazard lights on",
      "parking within 5 meters from a signalized intersection",
    ],
    answer: "parking within 5 meters from a signalized intersection",
  },
  {
    question: "When are you permitted to double park?",
    choices: [
      "Never",
      "When the street or road is wide enough",
      "When you have no other option",
    ],
    answer: "Never",
  },
  {
    question: "On a two-lane road, overtaking is only allowed only at the:",
    choices: ["left lane", "both right and left lanes", "right lane"],
    answer: "left lane",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following hand signals must a driver give when he wants to slow down and stop?",
    choices: [
      "Left arm is bent at elbow, hand pointing up",
      "Left arm held straight in horizontal position",
      "Left arm held down and hand pointing at ground",
    ],
    answer: "Left arm held down and hand pointing at ground",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When oncoming vehicle (car A) deliberately crosses the centerline to pass another vehicle, you (car B) should be:",
    choices: [
      "alert and be ready to slow down or stop if necessary",
      "blow your horn so he's alerted",
      "maintain your speed",
    ],
    answer: "alert and be ready to slow down or stop if necessary",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When two vehicles meet on a gradient road where neither cars pass, which of the two must yield?",
    choices: [
      "The vehicle going downhill",
      "The vehicle going uphill",
      "The vehicle that honks its horn first",
    ],
    answer: "The vehicle going downhill",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When driving on the highway at night, you should use low beam headlights (dim lights) when:",
    choices: [
      "another driver dims his lights",
      "blinded by the headlights of an approaching vehicle",
      "all of the above",
    ],
    answer: "all of the above",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Keeping one's distance lessens the risk of accident. One good rule is to leave a car length or:",
    choices: ["3-second rule", "4-second rule", "2-second rule"],
    answer: "2-second rule",
  },
  {
    question: "It is not a safe place to overtake in an/a:",
    choices: [
      "intersection and when approaching a bridge or a curve",
      "high speed road",
      "two lane road",
    ],
    answer: "intersection and when approaching a bridge or a curve",
  },
  {
    question: "The proper hand signal for right turn is:",
    choices: [
      "left arm bent at elbow, hand pointing up",
      "left arm held straight in horizontal position",
      "left arm held down and hand pointing at ground",
    ],
    answer: "left arm bent at elbow, hand pointing up",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The safest thing to do even if you have the rights of using the road is:",
    choices: ["don't force your rights", "horn", "force your rights"],
    answer: "don't force your rights",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the vehicle's headlight in front of you is blinding your eyes, what should you do?",
    choices: [
      "Quickly look on the right side of the road",
      "Look at the glaring light",
      "Put your headlight on high also",
    ],
    answer: "Quickly look on the right side of the road",
  },
  {
    question:
      'Upon approaching an intersection marked with a "Yield" sign, you are required to:',
    choices: [
      "stop before entering the intersection",
      "enter the intersection immediately",
      "slow down then enter the intersection when it is clear",
    ],
    answer: "slow down then enter the intersection when it is clear",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If you are driving in the wrong lane, what must you do to make a turn as you enter an intersection?",
    choices: [
      "Make the turn as quickly as possible",
      "Brake or clutch while turning so you won't overspeed",
      "Look behind on both sides and see if it is safe to change lane and make the turn",
    ],
    answer:
      "Look behind on both sides and see if it is safe to change lane and make the turn",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Using the shoulder of the road pass to the right of a car ahead of you is:",
    choices: [
      "allowed if you are turning right",
      "allowed if the car ahead is turning left",
      "against the law",
    ],
    answer: "against the law",
  },
  {
    question: "In a roundabout (rotunda), which has road rights?",
    choices: [
      "The vehicles facing the yellow light",
      "The vehicles already in the roundabout",
      "The vehicles approaching the roundabout",
    ],
    answer: "The vehicles already in the roundabout",
  },
  {
    question: "If the driver is turning left, he must: (U-turn / Left Rule)",
    choices: [
      "have the right of way",
      "do so slowly with caution",
      "yield to approaching cars",
    ],
    answer: "yield to approaching cars",
  },
  {
    question: "You may not cross a single broken white or yellow line:",
    choices: [
      "when turning left into a driveway",
      "when passing to the right on a one-way street",
      "when to do so would interfere with traffic",
    ],
    answer: "when to do so would interfere with traffic",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes the picture?",
    choices: ["Wide road ahead", "Narrow road ahead", "Slippery road"],
    answer: "Narrow road ahead",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the meaning of a blinking yellow traffic light?",
    choices: [
      "Stop and stay until light stops flashing",
      "Slow down and proceed with caution",
      "Wait for the green light",
    ],
    answer: "Slow down and proceed with caution",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Signs that are round, rectangular with white and blue background are called:",
    choices: ["warning signs", "informative signs", "regulatory signs"],
    answer: "informative signs",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the meaning of a traffic sign that has circle, octagon or reverse triangle with red color?",
    choices: ["Warning", "Giving direction", "Compulsory"],
    answer: "Compulsory",
  },
  {
    question: "Single broken line on a two-lane road means:",
    choices: [
      "the speed limit is 80kph",
      "you cannot overtake",
      "it separates traffic moving in opposite directions",
    ],
    answer: "it separates traffic moving in opposite directions",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes the picture?",
    choices: ["Slippery road", "Road construction", "Broken road"],
    answer: "Road construction",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes the picture?",
    choices: ["Intersection warning", "Train cannot pass", "Train track"],
    answer: "Train track",
  },
  {
    question: "When do you have a complete/full stop?",
    choices: [
      "at a flashing yellow traffic light",
      "at a green traffic light",
      "at a red traffic light",
    ],
    answer: "at a red traffic light",
  },
  {
    question: "What does this sign indicate?",
    choices: [
      "You may travel beyond 30 kph",
      "You must limit your speed to 30 kph",
      "The distance to the next town is 30 kph",
    ],
    answer: "You must limit your speed to 30 kph",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the meaning of a traffic sign that has a triangle with red color?",
    choices: ["Warning sign", "Reminder sign", "Information sign"],
    answer: "Warning sign",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes the picture?",
    choices: ["No entry", "Give way", "Stop"],
    answer: "Give way",
  },
  {
    question: "The signal warns of a hazard ahead:",
    choices: ["circle", "diamond", "triangle"],
    answer: "diamond",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes the picture?",
    choices: [
      "Dangerous curve on the left side",
      "Dangerous curve on the right side",
      "Intersection warning",
    ],
    answer: "Dangerous curve on the right side",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following best describes the picture?",
    choices: ["Slippery road", "Steep road", "Broken road"],
    answer: "Steep road",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It refers to an act penalizing a person under the influence of alcohol, dangerous drugs, and similar substances, and for other purposes.",
    choices: ["R.A. no. 10586", "R.A. no. 10585", "R.A. no. 10584"],
    answer: "R.A. no. 10586",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It shall mean that the LEO has reasonable ground to believe that the person driving the motor vehicle is under the influence of alcohol, dangerous drugs and/or other similar substances upon personally witnessing a traffic offense committed.",
    choices: ["improbable cause", "probable cause", "likely cause"],
    answer: "probable cause",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Operating a public utility vehicle equipped with stereo-music is punishable by:",
    choices: [
      "a fine of Php 1,000",
      "revocation of the license and registration certificate",
      "imprisonment of the driver and operator for six months",
    ],
    answer: "revocation of the license and registration certificate",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The motor vehicle plate and driver's license may be confiscated by any authorized LTO agent when the vehicle being operated is found to be:",
    choices: [
      "unsafe, unsightly, defective and dilapidated",
      "painted with color not approved by LTO",
      "inefficient",
    ],
    answer: "unsafe, unsightly, defective and dilapidated",
  },
  {
    question:
      "When a driver of PUV refuses to render service, convey passengers, such violation is penalized with:",
    choices: ["fine of ₱1,000", "fine of ₱2,000", "fine of ₱3,000"],
    answer: "fine of ₱3,000",
  },
  {
    question:
      "You were apprehended because you were engaged in car racing while driving in a super highway, what traffic violation did you commit?",
    choices: ["Reckless driving", "Gambling", "Overspeeding"],
    answer: "Reckless driving",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A type of field sobriety test that requires the driver to walk heel-to-toe along a straight line for nine (9) steps, turn at the end and return to the point of origin without any difficulty. What is this test called?",
    choices: [
      "The Cat-walk Test",
      "The Walk of Shame Test",
      "The Walk-and-turn",
    ],
    answer: "The Walk-and-turn",
  },
  {
    question: "Driving with a fake license is prohibited and is punishable by:",
    choices: [
      "Not more than 6 months of imprisonment",
      "Php 2,000.00 fine",
      "Php 3,000.00 fine with 12-month suspension of driver's license",
    ],
    answer: "Not more than 6 months of imprisonment",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A driver found to have been driving a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol, dangerous drugs and/or other similar substances, as provided for under section 5 of this Act, shall be penalized if the violation did not result in physical injuries or homicide with:",
    choices: [
      "six (6) months imprisonment, and a fine ranging from twenty thousand pesos (₱20,000.00) to eighty thousand pesos (₱80,000.00)",
      "twelve (12) months imprisonment, and a fine ranging from twenty thousand pesos (₱20,000.00) to eighty thousand pesos (₱80,000.00)",
      "three (3) months imprisonment, and a fine ranging from twenty thousand pesos (₱20,000.00) to eighty thousand pesos (₱80,000.00)",
    ],
    answer:
      "six (6) months imprisonment, and a fine ranging from twenty thousand pesos (₱20,000.00) to eighty thousand pesos (₱80,000.00)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The penalty of driving a motor vehicle while under the influence of alcohol for the first offense:",
    choices: [
      "non-professional driver’s license shall be confiscated and suspended for a period of twelve (6) months upon final conviction by a regular court",
      "non-professional driver’s license shall be confiscated and suspended for a period of twelve (12) months upon final conviction by a regular court",
      "non-professional driver’s license shall be confiscated and suspended for a period of twelve (24) months upon final conviction by a regular court",
    ],
    answer:
      "non-professional driver’s license shall be confiscated and suspended for a period of twelve (12) months upon final conviction by a regular court",
  },
  {
    question: "It refers to the amount of alcohol in a person’s blood.",
    choices: [
      "blood alcohol concentration (BAC)",
      "blood alcohol count (BAC)",
      "blood alcohol intake (BAI)",
    ],
    answer: "blood alcohol concentration (BAC)",
  },
  {
    question:
      "If the driver is using a motor vehicle in committing a crime and is convicted, his driver’s license shall be:",
    choices: [
      "revokes and will pay a fine",
      "confiscated and will pay fine",
      "suspended and will pay fine",
    ],
    answer: "suspended and will pay fine",
  },
  {
    question:
      "For drivers of trucks, buses, motorcycles and public utility vehicles, a BAC level of more than _____ shall be conclusive proof that said driver is driving under the influence of alcohol.",
    choices: ["0.20%", "0.00%", "0.30%"],
    answer: "0.00%",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The owner of a privately registered motor vehicle to be utilized for hire in the carriage of cargoes or passengers is penalized by:",
    choices: [
      "a fine of P2,000 and confiscation of vehicle plates",
      "a fine of P300",
      "confiscation of motor vehicle plates",
    ],
    answer: "a fine of P2,000 and confiscation of vehicle plates",
  },
  {
    question:
      "You were flagged down due to the noisy muffler of your motorcycle, what will you do?",
    choices: [
      "Bribe the traffic enforcer",
      "Reinstall the stock muffler of your motorcycle",
      "Pay the violation fee",
    ],
    answer: "Reinstall the stock muffler of your motorcycle",
  },
];
